

#### **CONTACT**

PHONE +256 702 515 243 +250 798 975 142

#### **Email**

muhammed\_riyas\_m@yahoo.in m.riyas.muhammed@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

- Full Stack Web Development
  MERN –React JS & Node JS
- SQL and Queries
- PHP
- SASS
- SAP Business one B1
- Inflow Inventory
- Store & Inventory
  Management
- HR Management
- Basic Accounts and Taxing
- Container offloading and handling
- Report Generation and analysis

# MUHAMMED RIYAS

#### **ABOUT ME**

Energetic Information technology master, Inventory, HR and System analysis with 8 + years of experience in administration and almost 2year experience in full stack web developer as well. I do have not only in good knowledge about I.T Basics, development and Electrical Retailing & Marketing but also have all-round experience with 10 years in different areas related with the same

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Operational Head & IT Manager, Tronic Electricals Ltd. Kigali, Rwanda July 2023 – still serving on

One of the leading Electrical Materials supplier dealing Manufacturing, Stocking and Retail and Wholesales Distributions in East Africa, focusing on TRONIC electrical products and appliances. I am working as operations & IT Manager for Rwanda branch since **July 2023** and work **permit no 00450255** holding H2 class visa, I deal taxing, purchase, inventory, sales and customer relationship all the areas of business. And I working as team leader of big number of staff and 3 warehouses as well.

#### Operational Manager & IT Manager, Tronic Uganda Ltd. Kampala June 2020 – June 2023

The leading Electrical Materials supplier in Uganda focusing on in TRONIC electrical products. I worked for the company as operational manger and IT head Permit no **EP 0053271 Class G2**. I promoted to administrative level for the company and member in core management team as well. Handled the implementation of Efris, SAP B1, inflow and POS.

## IT & Data Base engineer, Tronic Uganda Ltd, Kampala,Uganda. February 2017 – June 2020

The leading MNC in East Africa focusing especially in TRONIC electrical products. I am worked for the company since **02 Feb 2017** as I.T and Data Base Engineer, **permit no EP00**11**04**1 **with classG2 visa**, SAP B1

#### System Analyst, Cash Sales Store Ltd, Dar es Salaam Tanzania May 2015 - February 2017

The leading MNC in East Africa focusing especially in TRONIC electrical products. I worked in Tanzania under this company since 15 may 2015 as Computer system analyst, **permit no RPB1060191**. JD was report generating for sales, purchase and marketing and analyses to achieve the company target, reporting to country manager

## Software Engineer, NUCORE India Pvt Ltd, Calicut India November 2013 - April 2015

The Nucore is software solution in travel vertical industries as a MNC company serving in East Africa, Europe and gulf regions. I worked for this company as junior software developer end gradually reached at senior software engineer and team lead. Worked in Platform Linux and VSC, Zend 2 frame work, JQuery and JavaScript and Back end SQL

#### .Net Programmer, ACS Technologies, TVM

The ACS Technologies was a startup company for software and Automated solutions. I worked for this company as junior software developer.

#### ADDITIONAL SKILL

- Have Basic Idea about
  Electronics and Electricals.
- Computer Hardware & implementation
- Football & MMA
- Social Working

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor Degree of Computer Science, 2010 - 2013**

College of

Engineering, Attingal Under CUSAT University

#### Diploma in Computer Engineering, 2007 - 2010

SSM poly technical College, Tirur Under Technical Board of Kerala

### Vocational Higher Studies in Computer Science, 2005 - 2007

GVHSS, Pullanur Under State Board of Vocational Higher Studies Kerala